SUMMARY:

Highly motivated technology professional with a strong background in Data Analytics, Business Analysis, and Product Management. Demonstrated ability to design and implement effective solutions for data migration, reporting, and analytics projects. A value-driven contributor with experience managing cross-functional teams to develop SaaS products and enterprise-level projects.

EDUCATION:

The University of Chicago | Chicago, IL | MS Analytics December 2023 **Temple University** | Philadelphia, PA | BS Computer Science May 2019 Certification - Tableau Desktop Specialist Jul 2020 Certification - Certified Scrum Product Owner Feb 2022

EXPERIENCE:

ClearForMe, Philadelphia, PA

April 2021 – June 2022

(856) 602-6807

Product Owner II

- > Developed product strategy & roadmap aligned with the company's vision, market research, and customer feedback.
- Managed and groomed product backlog to bring strategic value to the business while meeting customer needs.
- ▶ Built CRM systems by building reports, dashboards, automation, and integrations to improve internal processes.
- Led the development effort for a new API product offering and the core platform used by 300+ businesses.
- Provided product operations and launch support to sales, customer support, finance, and marketing teams.

Cloud Mentor, Allentown, PA

May 2020 - March 2021

Technical Business Analyst

- Extracted data/files for multiple clients from various legacy systems (RDBMS, Flat Files, AWS, and Web Apps).
- > Prepared, presented, and communicated data mapping workbooks to the client for their approval.
- > Transformed data for loading into source systems using SOL, Excel, and ETL tools.
- > Designed and developed reports and dashboards by understanding customer need in Salesforce.
- > Built Python scripts to automate accounting data consolidation for the yearly and monthly tally.

Comcast, Philadelphia, PA

July 2019 – March 2020

Technical Business Analyst

- Architected the data migration process for a sunsetting legacy library system in under three months.
- > Designed and Documented Technical Solutions (UI/UX/Data Architecture) for new cloud-based applications.
- Developed reports and dashboards for senior stakeholders, power users, and administrators.
- Wrote Requirements, System Design documents, test cases, user stories, and operational documents.
- Collaborated with stakeholders, QA, and development team to provide feedback across all Legal Apps.

Slyce, Philadelphia, PA

Analytics Intern

January 2019 – May 2019

- > Created an Analytics portal for product and SDK offerings using Google Data Studio and BigQuery.
- > Built KPI reports on user retention, active users, and information on search types and top items.
- > Worked with Design and Embedded teams to assist in the product development of an In-store visual search offering.
- Utilized JIRA, AirTable, and Excel to help develop and train new Machine Learning models for new products.
- Worked with Sales to analyze Slyce's funnel to discover insights on opportunity and lead conversions.

Independence Blue Cross, Philadelphia, PA

Research Analyst Intern

October 2018 - May 2019

- > Performed research to find trends on various factors affecting health in the Philadelphia area.
- Facilitated focus groups, interviews, surveys, and desk research for primary and secondary research.
- > Partnered with informatics team to utilize IBC's Teradata Warehouse to analyze discovering insights using Tableau.
- > Developed a text analytics system to analyze 500+ user comments and feedback to discover patterns and sentiments.

Temple University, Dept. of BI and Data Management, Philadelphia, PA

BI & Data Management Developer Intern

October 2017 – December 2018

- > Created ETL jobs in ODI to create snapshots of key event points such as student registration and admissions.
- Worked with the DBA teams to push changes (ETL jobs, projects, and job schedules) to production.
- Migrated ETL jobs and schedules from the legacy Oracle Warehouse Builder tool to ODI to increase efficiency.
- Worked with BI team to deliver custom reports for various Departments/Business Units on IBM Cognos.